Finding Aid for the Richard G. Stearns Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Richard G. Stearns Papers
undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0417
10 linear_feet
- Structure & Waters Budget (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Final Orig. Porosity & HYD. etc. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Notes - Porosity for Water Level Changes (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Appendix - Christmas Mud (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Zurawski - Porosity of Carters Formation (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Plan of Foundation Exploration
- Plan of Reservoir Rim Exploration
- Percy Priest Reservoir, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers
- Borings - Log Sheet No.1, 6X Series (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Percy Priest Reservoir
- U.S. Army Corps of Engineers
- Borings - Log Sheet No.6 & 7, P-1 thru P-16, P-17 thru P-28 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Percy Priest Reservoir, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers
- Borings - Log Sheet No.8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Calyx Borings
- Percy Priest Reservoir, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers
- Borings - Log Sheet No.4 & 5 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 14-I thru 28-I, J and K Series, and 4-M, 6-M thru 28-M and R Series
- Percy Priest Reservoir, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers
- Borings - Log Sheet (Box 1, Folder 10)
- RL -1 thru RL-11, RL-13 thru RL-20, -2-P
- Percy Priest Reservoir, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers
- Borings - Log Sheet (Box 1, Folder 11)
- O-C, 2-E, 4-C, 32-C, U-31, C-1A thru C-12, C-13 thru C-21
- Percy Priest Reservoir, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers
- Borings - Log Sheet No. 2 & 3 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- C, D, and E Series and 11-G, 11-50G thru 22-G, 11-H, O-I thru 12+30I
- Percy Priest Reservoir, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers
  - (Materials of Nos. 5-12 are in the letter-size envelops, instead of folders)
    - Notes - Curd Rd. Test (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - R. G. Sterns, “Porosity and Hydrology of Jointed Middle Ordovician Limestone in the J. Percy Priest Dam Area of Central Tennessee”, (Oct. 1974) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Ron Smith, “Porosity of the Carter Limestone”, (Summer 1972) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Betsy Daniel, Appendix - Porosity for Road Cut Photos (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - TDWR Clark No.1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - TDWR Clark No.2 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - TDWR Clark No.3 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - A. T. Woodard Water Well (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Rockdale Hill Section (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Shady Grove-Staggs Section (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Test Well Site: Detail Map (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Skillman Basin Maps (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Fort Payne Samples I-40 & I-65 (also some duplicate notes on RH) (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - LS & Chert Petrography Notes - RH I-40 & I-65 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - OWRR (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Small Basin (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Small Basin - Unassigned (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - R. G. STEARNS, “Geochemistry & Geohydrology of a Small Basin in the Upper Buffalo River Watershed, Tennessee”, (period: Jul. 1969 - Jun. 1970) (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Floyd C. Larson - General (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Small Basin Budget, (1968-69) (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Small Basin Budget, (1969-70) (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - A Notebook (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Tests - Hoover Quarry (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Hoover Quarry - Metro Airport (in a letter-size envelop) (Box 1, Folder 36)
- R. G. Stearns, Physical Geology Textbook, (Fall 1983) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Syllabus and Schedule - Sections 7-10 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Geology 101 - Physical Geology - Fall, 1993
- Nalco Chemical (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Tests and Exams - Geology 102, Historical Geology, Early 1970s (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Geology 150 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- May Term 94 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- May Term 93 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- May Term 92 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- CPLE Reviews (Box 2, Folder 9)
- May Term 90 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- May Term 91 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- May Term 89 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Geology 150, (1985-89) (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Geology 150, (1984-85) (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Geology 150, (1981) (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Geology 240, (Spring 1994) (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Syllabus and Schedule - Geology 255 - Exploration Geophysics, (Fall 1993) (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, Notes, Photos, etc. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- New Madrid, News, Notes & Correspondence, Buscchbach & Stever, etc. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - A (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - B (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - C (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Computer (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - D (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - E (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Fencing Team (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - G (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Grants (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Gravity Meter & Grav. Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - H (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - I (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - J (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - K (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - L (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Leave, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - LUMM (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - M (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Memorial CWW (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Misc. Curiosa, etc. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - N (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - O (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Promotions, 1984-88-93 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - P & Q (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - R (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - S (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - T (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Travel (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - U & United Way (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - USGS & Cape Girardeau, Missouri (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - V (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - WX (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Water File (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - YZ (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Consistent Maps (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Earthquakes (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Old Stone Fort (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Preliminary Paleogeography (F-’1) & (D-2, E) (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Misc. USGS, NSF, TVA (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - GEOL. OF TENN. (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - GSA New Orleans (National Meeting 1967) (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Stress and Faulting, Ronald C. Bass, Spring, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Joint Poles, 1970 - I-40 E of McCray Lane (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Earthquakes & Earth’s Interior, NS 101, Nov. 1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- GEOL 240 1968 & 1969 - Hermitage, Tenn, Qud. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Student Papers and Reports on I-40 Joint Project (Box 4, Folder 5)
- GEOL 240, 1966, 1968, 1973, 1987, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- GEOL 240 - Past Course Reports, 1980-90 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- GEOL 240 - LAB, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- GEOL 240 - Notes, etc., 1977 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- GEOL 240 - LAB, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- GEOL 240, Spring 1991-1994 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- How to write “Term Paper” (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Geophysics & Ind Study (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Geophysics (Box 4, Folder 14)
- GEOL 101 - Fall 1986-87 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- GEOL 101 - Fall, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Geophysics (GEOL 285), 1989 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- GEOL 101 - Fall, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- GEOL 101 - Spring 1991 & Fall, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- GEOL 101 - 1992-93 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Historical Geology (Box 4, Folder 21)
- R. G. Stearn’s Nootbook (Sedimentation & principles of Stratigraphy) (Box 5, Folder 1)
- R. G. Stearn’s Nootbook (Plant Anatomy & Microtechnique) (Box 5, Folder 2)
- R. G. Stearn’s Nootbook (Biology 421) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- R. G. Stearn’s Nootbook (Geology - Structural) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- R. G. Stearn’s Nootbook (Biology 323B) (Box 5, Folder 5)
- R. G. Stearn’s Nootbook (Biology 323A) (Box 5, Folder 6)
- R. G. Stearn’s Nootbook (Paleontology) (Box 5, Folder 7)
- R. G. Stearn’s Class Notes (323A) (Box 5, Folder 8)
- R. G. Stearn’s Class Notes (Morphology of Vascular Plants) (Box 5, Folder 9)
- R. G. Stearn’s Class Notes (Paleontology) (Box 5, Folder 10)
- R. G. Stearn’s Class Notes (Structural Geology) (Box 5, Folder 11)
- R. G. Stearn’s Class Notes (Paleobotany - 1949) (Box 5, Folder 12)
- R. G. Stearn’s Class Notes (Paleobotany) (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Geology D-4 Lab Report - Sedimentation (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Geology D-4 - Sedimentation (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Syllabus - Geology C-2, (Fall 1949) (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Geology D-5 - Laboratory Exercises, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Geophysics & Geochem. Principles, D-12-13-14, (1950-51) (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Pottsville & Equivalents - Regional Analysis, (1950) (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Petrology & Petrography (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Syllabus Geology D-5 Biostratigraphy, Sedimentary Facies, & Principles of Correlation (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Dissertation Proposals (Box 5, Folder 22)
- USGS - Groundwater Course (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Groundwater Geology & Hydrology, U.S. Geol Survey Short Course (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Statistics Class Notes (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Math 230 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Engineering Math & Mechanics Analyt. Geol & Calculus I & II Vector Statistics, Mech. of Materials Soil Mech. & Fluid Mech., (Fall 1967-71) (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Stratigraphy, (Fall 1964-5) (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Mineralogy (Box 6, Folder 2)
- C. W. Wilson - “Published” a Set of Notes on Historical Geology (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Stratigraphy Notes (Box 6, Folder 4)
- 1966 - Notes on Historical Geology by C. W. Wilson, Jr. (Box 6, Folder 5)
- 1948 or Earlier - Notes on Historical Geology Stearns was a student in 1945-49) (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Report Preparation (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Structure Exam, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- “An Investigation into the Physics and Chemistry of the Earth’s Core” (Allen Zack, April 18, 1966) (Box 6, Folder 9)
- “Is the Earth Shrinking or Expanding? (Clyde Lee, April 19, 1966) (Box 6, Folder 10)
- “Some Theories Concerning the Origin of the Continents, with Emphasis on Accretion vs. Convection” (Richard C. Finch, April 18, 1966) (Box 6, Folder 11)
- “Continental Draft: An Argument for Tidal Forces” (Charles M. Woodruff, Jr. April 18, 1966) (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Structure Lab (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Structure Lab (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Structure Report, (1963) (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Student Papers for Structural Geology, (May 1971) (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Student Papers and Reports (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Section Report by R. Bass (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Stratig Reports, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Richard Stearns: Math. B-11-12 Calculus (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Richard Stearns: Isopach & Lithofacies Maps (1951, at Northwestern) (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Richard Stearns: “Metamorphism of the Blue Ridge - Piedmont Province from PA-GA” (1951, at Northwestern) (Box 6, Folder 22)
- 1968 Geology Department Planning Document (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Minutes of the Meeting of the Panel on Liberal Arts Education in Geological Sciences (Jan. 14-5, 1966, SMU, Dallas, Texas) (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Structure Notes (C. W. Wilson, Jr.) (Box 6, Folder 25)
- General Athletic Committee (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Northwestern University Athletics (Box 7, Folder 2)
- General Athletic Committee (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Athletics (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Campus Setting Committee (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Geo Study (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Technology and Human Values (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Chess Club (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Rec. Int & Club Sp., 1988 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- University Club (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Club Sports, etc., 1977-1980 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Interamurals, Club S., PE., 1980 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- PE Report, September 1980 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Interamurals, 1980-84 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Recreation Facility, 1984-86 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Recreation Committee, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- CPLE Natural Science Subcommittee (Box 7, Folder 17)
- CPLE Geology 101, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Vanderbilt University Riele Team, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- FRATS (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Faculty/Staff Campaign, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- AAUP (Box 7, Folder 22)
- A.I.P.G.S. (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Geology Department (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Graduate Student Assistants (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Tenn. Dir. Geology (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Teaching Assistant Students (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Higham (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Metro Airport, Quarry (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Huddleston Area, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Airport - Geologic Mapping for Engineering Use (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Harpeth UTIL (Bob Parker, Dennis Willis), 1987 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- 1964-1966 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- TVA - LBL, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Buntin Case (Walter Grouch), 1976 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Tennessee Valley Authority (Box 8, Folder 9)
- T.V.A. - Miscellaneous & Financial (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Business End of Geology (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Sardis Report CE., 1978 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Krinitzsky Usage Project (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Geologial-Seismological Investigation of Earthquake hazards at Sardis Dam, Mississippi, Final Report, June 1979 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Yazoo River Basin, Mississippi, Sardis Lake, Little Tallahatchie River, Sardis Dam Earthquake Study, Sellection of a Design Earthquake, Nov. 1976 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Barkley Dam Report (Box 8, Folder 16)
- R. G. Stearns, “Earthquake & Geology of the Barkley Dam Area in Relation to the New Madrid Earthquake Region” (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Phi Beta Kappa (Box 9, Folder 1)
- R. G. Stearns as a Student at Vanderbilt 1948-49 Correspondence - Graduate School applications Bank Record Drawings for Professor C. W. Wilson, Jr. (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Bank Statements, Fall 1982-1988 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Bank Accounts and Statements, 1972, August 1976 (Box 9, Folder 4)